SASCHA ANDEWEG

LINGUISTIC DATA ANALYST / JUNIOR FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER / GRAPHIC DESIGNER /

20 Hawthorn Crescent Forest Glen, P61K253 Fermoy, Co. Cork T: 089 7028 790 E: sascha@designed.irish

Many years of experience in the printing business in The Netherlands, creating bespoke products for clients that I built long lasting working relationships with. Developing ideas with the client and designing and producing material for print and web with my team were rewarding, enjoyable and gave me priceless experience. After moving to Ireland with my family in 2016 I started working for a multinational as a linguistic data analyst/modeler in AI/ML within an international team. This gives me the confidence that after my recent graduation from the Code Institute and getting a level 6 diploma in **Full Stack Software Development** I can again successfully evolve into a role that may require many

EDUCATION

of the qualities I have developed.

2019 - 2020	Second Class Honours	DIPLOMA IN SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT	CodeInstitute, Dublin, Ireland
2011		WORKSHOP COLUMN WRITING	Marjon Sarneel, The Netherlands
2010	Certificate	TRAINING 'EXPERT IN SALES'	Kenneth Smit, The Netherlands
1999	Certificate	DREAMWEAVER/FLASH COURSE	GOC, Rotterdam, The Netherlands
1998	Certificate	BASIC WEBDESIGN AND HTML	GOC, Rotterdam, The Netherlands
1990-1991	Diploma	GRAPHIC TECHNICIAN PREPRESS	GOC, Rotterdam, The Netherlands
1988-1990	Diploma	BASIC PREPRESS	GOC, Rotterdam, The Netherlands
1985		TYPING	NHI, Terneuzen, The Netherlands
1985-1988	Diploma	LEAVING CERT	Zwin College, Oostburg, The Netherlands

EXPERIENCE

2016 - present GLOBETECH LTD.

Linguistic Data Analyst

Linguistic analysis and modelling for artificial intelligence and machine learning. Due to a non-disclosure contract I can not share further details about the position.

2004- present

FESTIVAL VAN ZEEUWSCH-VLAANDEREN

Web Designer - Graphic Designer

As freelancer I build the <u>website</u> for this music festival every year. In consultation with my former employer mr. Bareman I could continue this work for the festival.

1985 - 2016

DRUKKERIJ BAREMAN / TEKSTBEELD GROEP

Prepress specialist / Graphic Designer

Graphic Designer

- Excellent IT skills, especially with Adobe CC design and photo-editing software.
- Creativity and innovation where needed or follow strict guidelines where corporate styles demand it.
- Excellent time management and organisational skills to meet deadlines and work with the in-house printing department.
- Accuracy and attention to detail.
- An understanding of the latest trends and their role within a commercial environment.
- Professional approach to time, costs and deadlines.
- A personal approach towards clients to build long lasting relationships.

Prepress

- Preparing designs for printing (offset and digital), inpositioning and offset-plate making.
- Operating digital printers (large format inkjet and laser).

Web Design

- From quotation, planning, to design, copywriting and deployment.
- Managing maintenance subscriptions and support.

IT-support

- On-site IT-support for the branch (Windows-servers, networking, security).
- Advisory role for computer hardware on the graphic design department.

Sales and publishing

Produced the lay-out for a local magazine, managed/coordinated the editorial content and coordinated the
acquisition of adverts. Occasionally I would assist in the acquisition of advertisements and writing editorial material.

SASCHA ANDEWEG

LINGUISTIC DATA ANALYST / JUNIOR FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER / GRAPHIC DESIGNER /

2006 - 2016 RAMMELOO COMMUNICATIONS

Graphic Designer

As freelancer I produced the layout, including many of the adverts, of a local paper and created presentation material.

VOLUNTEERING

- present

I help scheduling and managing the exchange of weekly public talks between locations and also participate as a public speaker.

SKILLS

- Data Analysis Managing data for AI/ML
- Graphic Design Well versed in the Adobe CC software and Microsoft Office
- Junior Full Stack Software Developer Trained in:
 HTML CSS Bootstrap JavaScript test driven development (Jasmine) using API's JQuery Python Flask MySQL MongoDB Postgres Django Git

(SOCIAL) MEDIA

- LinkedIn
- Portfolio

HOBBIES/INTERESTS

- Improvised music
- Photography
- Graphic Design
- The power of language

REFERENCES

On request